

I am Adam Kosecki, a highly-analytical product developer with 10+ years of experience. I create things that are clean; from beautiful, straightforward, comprehensible design elements to robust & readable code.

I strive to understand a problem from all angles before outlining a solution. My solutions are a fair compromise between form and function, fanciness and efficiency, seriousness and fun.

I am a leader. I make decisions when appropriate, and defer or delegate without shame. People respect me and enjoy working with me.

#### 847-528-2326 adamkosecki@gmail.com

full resume at: adamkosecki.com

### **TECH & TOOLS**

JS, Ember.JS, Cordova, Bootstrap, MySQL, Sphinx Full-Text Search, PHP, Phalcon, AWS, Photoshop, Illustrator AWS

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Programming Emphasis
Minor in Psychology

Western Illinois University 2000-2004

#### **HISTORY**

### SpotMii

CO-FOUNDER/DEVELOPER

SpotMii was created to provide fitness consumers a way to discover new and exciting fitness facilities, and streamline the payment and check-in process for individuals that frequent multiple gyms. Users purchase single-use passes for drop-in access and scheduled classes. Payments and scheduling are handled in-app.

As a co-founder of SpotMii, I successfully designed, built, and deployed demonstrative beta versions of our apps that enabled us to secure an angel round of funding. I completed and launched vI of the app in early 2019.

- · Geo-located, on-demand, two-sided marketplace
- Single codebase SPA/JS/Cordova app deployed to iOS App Store and Google Play
- Three apps built and deployed: Consumer facing app, affiliate app for gym owners, and an intranet for internal moderation.
- Ember.js SPA design & implementation
- · PHP/Phalcon API design & implementation
- MySQL DBA
- AWS infrastructure

### MogulMind

CO-FOUNDER/DEVELOPER 2016-2018 I designed and built MogulMind: an Ember.js SPA that provides insight into real estate investments, helping users increase their ROI and make better investment decisions. MogulMind is a first-to-market web app providing traditional RE investment calculations for the modern world, as well as proprietary investment advice through AI.

As the founder's first partner, I took MogulMind from napkin idea to launch and customer acquisition. I was the root of anything technical or design related.

- · SPA: Ember.js design & implementation
- REST API: PHP/Phalcon/MySQL design & implementation
- · Marketing website design & implementation
- AWS infrastructure

#### Clear Software

VP of Product / Lead Developer 2015-2016 Transitioned Clear Software from an on-premise, single-user solution to a multitenant, SaaS, cloud application. Evangelized best practices and modern development techniques.



847-528-2326 adamkosecki@gmail.com

# HISTORY (continued)

## HelpSystems

Senior Developer 2015-2016 / Contract 2014-2015 Full Time \* HelpSystems acquired Network Automation (below)

Developed and deployed an HTML5, mobile-first invoicing application in PHP/ AngularJS/MySql to facilitate an end-to-end process for online purchases and payment collection. The application included a robust API allowing it to integrate with multiple, disparate back-end legacy systems.

Implemented ETL processes to migrate and synchronize data between HelpSystems and Network Automation servers throughout the acquisition process.

## **Network Automation**

Lead Developer, UI Design 2005-2015 Created entire public web entity for company (no longer online as of 2019), including all visual design elements, technological decisions (language/framework/server), coding, SEO decisions, optimization for user experience & retention, and... everything else:

- Built a homegrown shopping cart system: processed every purchase/transaction made through the company. Responsible not only for collecting payment, but issuing products and licenses to customers.
- Built a homegrown Customer Resource Center: video tutorials, knowledge-base articles, product version history, etc. Included an internal CMS.
- Built a homegrown, drag-n-drop HTML email creation tool for our newsletters (Mailchimp before Mailchimp). Integrated with our blog, etc. to easily drag-n-drop existing articles to create an HTML newsletter. Included mass-mailing system and subscription management.
- · Built a homegrown support ticketing system.
- Built a homegrown Channel/Partner Portal: an application to provide sales collateral, news, lead registration, etc for resellers/VARs/strategic partners.
- Built our homegrown customer account application (address info, license keys, product maintenance subscriptions, etc).
- Marketing and pre-sale content: press releases, news, case studies, blog.
- Served as company DBA, implementing best practices including full
  normalization of existing MS SQL database. Wrote and revised countless queries,
  views, and stored procedures for various organizational departments.
- Inherited, managed, enhanced, and enriched existing (homegrown) corporate CRM.